pressurecookrecipes.com 2018-12-30

# Privacy Policy | Pressure Cook Recipes

This privacy policy sets out how PressureCookRecipes.com uses and protects any information that you give us when you use this website. PressureCookRecipes.com is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy and terms of service. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

PressureCookRecipes.com may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from Oct 26, 2018.

 **Information we may gather  **

We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent;

 **Newsletter:**  On PressureCookRecipes.com, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows us to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

 **Browsing our Site** : Just like all the websites on the internet, the platform we are on will automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website.

 **Nutritional Facts:  **We attempt to maintain the accuracy of the information provided on the Website, but we are not certified health professionals or nutritionists, thus, we do not guarantee the complete accuracy or inclusiveness of the information including the nutrition information provided on Nutrition Facts Labels with the recipes. The nutrition information are provided as a general reference for the readers, users, or anyone else at the courtesy of online nutrition calculators such as caloriecount.com. The nutrition information is not a substitute for professional advice by certified health professionals.

It is understood that you, as the reader and user of the Website, will indemnify and hold the Website, its owner, agents, and employees harmless from any loss, expense of any nature, or any other liability for all claims for damages arising out of the use of any portion of the data and content provided on the Website and any other related channels.

 **Comments:  **When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

 **How your information may be used**

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

To send you newsletter. Each email will provide information on how to opt-out of future emails;  
To respond to your comments, email inquiries, and questions;  
To measure the performance and readability of the website  
To operate our site and tailor our site in our readers’ best interest;

 **Google** – Additionally, we use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”).

Google Analytics analyze how users use PressureCookRecipes.com. The information generated about your use (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of PressureCookRecipes.com, compiling reports on activity for its staff and providing other services relating to web page activity and internet usage.

Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf.

 **Affiliate Program Participation –   **The Site may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Site. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

 **Amazon** – PressureCookRecipes.com is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com, Amazon.ca, Amazon.co.uk. As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Site will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales. If you decide to purchase items on this site, Amazon will send a small commission to support Pressure Cook Recipes at no additional costs to you. These commissions will help cover our operation costs to keep this site running.

 **Facebook** – With your permission, our website utilizes the Conversion Tracking Pixel service of Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave., Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (“Facebook”). This tool allows us to follow the actions of users after they are redirected to a provider’s website by clicking on a Facebook advertisement. We are thus able to record the efficacy of Facebook advertisements for statistical and market research purposes. The collected data remain anonymous. This means that we cannot see the personal data of any individual user.

 **Histats** – We may use this service to collect statistical data about the visit to improve the ergonomics of our site, as well as improving the range and quality of services that we have to offer. This data provides information that relates to the type of browser that is used, the number of page views, the exact path that an Internet user has taken on a site, the amount of time spent on a page, site etc. 

No primary personal information such as first name, surname, telephone number, email address, etc, is collected by any of the Histats solutions. Use the following link if you wish to optout from histats tracking service http://www.histats.com/optOut.php

 **Security**  – We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

 **How we use cookies** A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyze web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system. Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

(a) <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);

(b) <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences> (Firefox);

(c) <http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/> (Opera);

(d) <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies> (Internet Explorer);

(e) <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and

(f) [https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows–10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy) (Edge).

 **What Rights We Have Over Your Data –  **If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

 **Links to other websites**  – Our website may contain links to enable you to visit other websites of interest easily. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

 **Advertising Privacy Statement**

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can [contact us here](https://www.pressurecookrecipes.com/contact-us/) ** ** and contact AdThrive. If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences link at the bottom of the site. (Available in the EU.)

 **Additional Rights of EEA (European Economic Area) Residents**

If you are a resident of a country in the EEA, you have the rights, among others, to:

(i) access your personal data

(ii) ensure the accuracy of your personal data

(iii) the right to have us delete your personal data

(iv) the right to restrict further processing of your personal data, and

(v) the right to complain to a supervisory authority in your country of residence in the event that data is misused

If you believe that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us thru our contact form.

If you have any questions or concerns, please [contact us here](https://www.pressurecookrecipes.com/contact-us/)
